dunkelindex.com 2003-06-21

# The DUNKEL INDEX

The News-Journal is committed to bringing you the best possible online experience that we can provide. One important aspect of that experience is ensuring that you are aware of when and how the News-Journal collects information about you and how that information is used. We believe that this policy effectively balances your privacy and our collection of necessary information to enhance our services to you. 

This privacy policy applies only to News-Journal Online and the News-Journal family of websites. It does not reflect the News-Journal's offline privacy policies. 

The News-Journal's collection of information is limited to those circumstances where it is necessary to the proper and effective functioning of News-Journal Online. We do not sell your personal information. Electronic mail sent to News-Journal Online will be retained only so long as it is necessary for technical or legal purposes and is then deleted. 

**IP Address**

Your Internet Protocol (IP) address is collected automatically when you access News-Journal Online so that we may identify your computer should we ever need to for technical or legal purposes. We do not use this information to track your movements on News-Journal Online, and it is not shared with any other party. 

**News-Journal Center**

News-Journal Online offers the opportunity for you to discuss issues relevant to our community and our world in our News-Journal Center discussion boards. Personal information that you disclose in these boards is immediately available to anyone who chooses to access this area of News-Journal Online, so please be responsible with your personal information. For more ideas for using News-Journal Center responsibly, please visit our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.news-journalonline.com/online/terms.htm) page. 

News-Journal Center is the only area on News-Journal Online that uses cookies. Cookies are small files that are deposited on the hard drive of your computer in order to save your selected preferences where they can be read by our site. News-Journal Center uses cookies to identify which messages in News-Journal Center are new since your last visit, and, if you desire, to store your username and password so that you do not have to log in each time you visit News-Journal Center. Users with cookies disabled on their computers will lose this convenience, but are still able to use our message boards. 

In order to register for News-Journal Center, you are required to provide us with your user name and email address. This information is used to verify your password and to contact you in the event that there is a problem with your account. The remainder of the information requested is optional. If you do elect to provide the optional information, it is available to anyone who clicks on the profile icon at the top of your posted messages. 

Children under 13 are not permitted to register for News-Journal Center. For more information on the News-Journal's compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, please visit our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.news-journalonline.com/online/terms.htm) page. 

**Subscription Renewal and Classified Advertisements**

The News-Journal offers you the opportunity to renew your subscription to The Daytona Beach News-Journal or place a classified advertisement online. The News-Journal collects a significant amount of personal information about you in order to fulfill these requests. The News-Journal only uses this information for the express purpose for which you provide it and does not share it internally or externally for any other purpose. 

**Affiliate Websites**

The News-Journal has partnered with other companies that provide additional services in association with News-Journal Online. These companies have their own information collection and privacy policies that may or may not be the same as the News-Journal's policies. Whenever you have the opportunity to visit one of our affiliate sites, please review their privacy policy before using their services.   
Our affiliate sites are: 

* 1\. [Online Coupons](http://www.clipacoupon.com/?aff=njo) \- This page is managed by [ClipACoupon.com](http://www.clipacoupon.com/). You may access their privacy policy [here](http://www.clipacoupon.com/privacy.asp?aff=njo). 
* 2\. [News-JournalAutos.com](http://www.news-journalautos.com/) \- This site is managed by [CarCast](http://www.carcast.com/). You may contact them [here](http://www.poweradz.com/contactus/hd_mail.html). 
* 3\. TV listings - These are provided by Zap2It.com. You may access their privacy policy [here](http://www.zap2it.com/index/0,1146,4_B_0_000,00.html). 

**Third Party Ad Networks**

ValueClick, Inc. provides some of the News-Journal Online advertisements. ValueClick's policies regarding information collection and privacy are available at <http://www.valueclick.com/privacy.html>. 

**Links**

News-Journal Online contains links to other web sites and other web sites contain links to News-Journal Online. The News-Journal is not responsible for the content or information practices of these linked sites. 

**Promotions and Contests**

When a promotion or contest is provided through News-Journal Online, we may collect personally identifiable information about you in order to allow you to participate. Unless specifically disclosed during the registration process, this information will not be disclosed to anyone other than the News-Journal employees and agents necessary to the proper performance of the promotion or contest. 

**Compliance with Legal Process or Emergency**

The News-Journal reserves the right to disclose any and all information necessary if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect or defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of News-Journal Online; or (4) protect the safety or property of any person or entity. 

**Aggregate Data**

Aggregate data is that information which tracks activity on News-Journal Online as a whole and is not identified with you personally. This information includes your Internet Service Provider, your operating system, and your browser. This information is collected for the purpose of determining the areas of our site that users most enjoy and to tailor our site to the equipment and software used by our users. 

**Changes to this Policy**

By using this web site, you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this policy. The News-Journal reserves the right to change its privacy policy and practices at any time without notice.
